Guide to the Taube Archive of the International Military Tribunal (IMT) at Nuremberg, 1945-46 mt839rq8746
Virtual Tribunals
Taube Archive of the International Military Tribunal (IMT) at Nuremberg
1945-46
Virtual Tribunals
International Court of Justice. Library
International Military Tribunal
mt839rq8746
9920 item(s)
Scope and Contents
The Taube Archive of the International Military Tribunal (IMT) at Nuremberg, 1945-46 collection includes court transcripts, indictments, sentences, briefings, minutes, etc, related to the proceedings of the International Military Tribunal (IMT) at Nuremberg. The first twenty-eight boxes contain: a) Exhibits submitted to the Tribunal by Prosecution and Defense; b) Official Transcripts as taken by Court Reporters, of Court and Commission proceedings; c) Document Books of Prosecution and Defense; d) Trial Briefs, Opening and Closing Statements of Prosecution; e) Final Pleas and Clemency Pleas of Defense; f) Indictment; g) Judgement, Dissenting Opinion and Sentences; h) Minutes of Tribunal Meetings; i) Rules of the Tribunal, Orders of the Tribunal, Court Rulings on the Final Record; and j) Lists, indices and miscellaneous related material. Material was inventoried box by box. The last nine boxes contain only electronic transcriptions of the proceedings before the International Military Tribunal.
The digital collection contains approximately 250,000 pages of digitized paper documents (transcripts of the hearings in English, French, German and Russian; written pleadings; evidence exhibits filed by the prosecution and the defense; documents of the Committee for the Investigation and Prosecution of Major War Criminals; the judgment).
The official archives of the International Military Tribunal of Nuremberg (the "Nuremberg Trial Archives") were entrusted to the International Court of Justice (ICJ) in 1950. The ICJ and its Registry are the custodians of the entire archive, which includes the original print documents that are available in digital form here, audio recordings of the trial's proceedings, and evidentiary films.
Source: The Registry, International Court of Justice. (2018). Nuremberg Trial Archives, The International Court of Justice: Custodian of the archives of the International Military Tribunal at Nuremberg (2nd ed.) and the United States Holocaust Memorial Museum
International Military Tribunal (IMT) Cases
The IMT's single case tried 24 defendants, all charged with being "leaders, organizers [and] instigators [of] and accomplices" in the crimes defined in the Charter. They were chosen to represent a cross-section of Nazi diplomatic, economic, political, and military leadership. Adolf Hitler, Heinrich Himmler, and Joseph Goebbels could not be tried because they committed suicide at the end of the war or soon afterwards. Hermann Göring was the highest ranking Nazi official among the defendants.
In the end, only 21 defendants appeared in court. German industrialist Gustav Krupp was included in the original indictment, but he was elderly and in failing health. The Tribunal decided in preliminary hearings to exclude him from the proceedings. Nazi Party secretary Martin Bormann could not be located. Borman was thus tried in absentia. Head of the German Labor Front Robert Ley committed suicide on the eve of the trial. (United States Holocaust Memorial Museum)
Joining the lead defendant, Reichsmarschall and Successor Designate to Hitler, Hermann Wilhelm Goering, were:
Rudolf Hess, former Deputy to the Führer;Joachim von Ribbentrop, Reich Minister for Foreign Affairs;Wilhelm Keitel, Chief of the High Command of the German Armed Forces;Ernst Kaltenbrunner, Head of the Reich Main Security Office and highest ranking officer of the Nazi party Schutzstaffel (SS) at Nuremberg;Alfred Rosenberg, racial theory ideologist and Reich Minister for the Eastern Occupied Territories;Hans Frank, Governor General of the Occupied Polish Territories;Wilhelm Frick, Reich Minister of the Interior and Reich Protector for Bohemia and Moravia;Julius Streicher, Editor-in-Chief of the antisemitic newspaper Der Stürmer;Walther Funk, Reich Minister of Economics and President of the German Reichsbank;Hjalmar Schacht, former Reich Minister of Economics and President of the German Reichsbank;Karl Doenitz, Commander-in-Chief of the German Navy and, briefly, successor to Hitler as Head of the German Government;Erich Raeder, former Commander-in-Chief of the German Navy;Baldur von Schirach, Head of the Hitler Youth;Fritz Sauckel, Plenipotentiary of the Nazi slave-labour programme;Alfred Jodl, Chief of the High Command of the German Armed Forces Operations Department;Franz von Papen, former Reich Chancellor and Vice Chancellor;Arthur Seyss-Inquart, Reich Commissar for the Occupied Netherlands;Albert Speer, Reich Minister for Armament and Munitions and Hitler's chief architect;Konstantin von Neurath, Reich Minister of Foreign Affairs and later Reich Protector for Bohemia and Moravia; and Hans Fritzsche, Ministerialdirektor of the Reich Ministry of Propaganda. International Military Tribunal (IMT) Crimes
Article 6 of the IMT's Charter listed three broad categories of crimes:
IMT's Charter
(a) Crimes against peace: namely, planning, preparation, initiation or waging of a war of aggression, or a war in violation of international treaties, agreements or assurances, or participation in a common plan or conspiracy for the accomplishment of any of the foregoing; (b) War crimes: namely, violations of the laws or customs of war. Such violations shall include, but not be limited to, murder, ill-treatment or deportation to slave labour or for any other purpose of civilian population of or in occupied territory, murder or ill-treatment of prisoners of war or persons on the seas, killing of hostages, plunder of public or private property, wanton destruction of cities, towns or villages, or devastation not justified by military necessity; (c) Crimes against humanity: namely, murder, extermination, enslavement, deportation, and other inhumane acts committed against any civilian population, before or during the war, or persecutions on political, racial or religious grounds in execution of or in connection with any crime within the jurisdiction of the Tribunal, whether or not in violation of the domestic law of the country where perpetrated.
The first of these charges, (a), was subdivided in the indictment, which thus contained four counts, of which the defendants each faced his own permutation. Count one (common plan or conspiracy) was prosecuted by the United States, and count two (crimes against peace) by the United Kingdom. Count three (war crimes) and count four (crimes against humanity) were prosecuted jointly by France and the Soviet Union, according to whether the crimes in question had been committed in Western or Eastern Europe.
Zeppelinfeld (Nuremberg, Germany); Nuremberg War Crime Trials, Nuremberg, Germany, 1946-1949; International criminal courts; Trials (Crimes against humanity); Criminal procedure (International law); Crimes against humanity; International Court of Justice. Library; International Military Tribunal
- Audio recordings of proceedings, 4361 item(s)
  Scope and Contents
  Contemporaneous audio recordings of the complete trial proceedings at the IMT Nuremberg, from reading of the indictments, to opening statements, the presentation and cross-examination of evidence at trial, closing statements and final judgments.
  - November 1945, 187 item(s)
    - November 20, 1945, 27 item(s)
    - November 21, 1945, 21 item(s)
    - November 22, 1945, 21 item(s)
    - November 23, 1945, 20 item(s)
    - November 26, 1945, 20 item(s)
    - November 27, 1945, 20 item(s)
    - November 28, 1945, 18 item(s)
    - November 29, 1945, 20 item(s)
    - November 30, 1945, 20 item(s)
  - December 1945, 325 item(s)
    - December 1, 1945, 14 item(s)
    - December 3, 1945, 20 item(s)
    - December 4, 1945, 22 item(s)
    - December 5, 1945, 21 item(s)
    - December 6, 1945, 22 item(s)
    - December 7, 1945, 24 item(s)
    - December 10, 1945, 25 item(s)
    - December 11, 1945, 20 item(s)
    - December 12, 1945, 22 item(s)
    - December 13, 1945, 25 item(s)
    - December 14, 1945, 24 item(s)
    - December 17, 1945, 23 item(s)
    - December 18, 1945, 22 item(s)
    - December 19, 1945, 22 item(s)
    - December 20, 1945, 19 item(s)
  - January 1946, 504 item(s)
    - January 2, 1946, 21 item(s)
    - January 3, 1946, 24 item(s)
    - January 4, 1946, 23 item(s)
    - January 7, 1946, 25 item(s)
    - January 8, 1946, 23 item(s)
    - January 9, 1946, 22 item(s)
    - January 10, 1946, 25 item(s)
    - January 11, 1946, 23 item(s)
    - January 14, 1946, 12 item(s)
    - January 15, 1946, 25 item(s)
    - January 16, 1946, 26 item(s)
    - January 17, 1946, 22 item(s)
    - January 18, 1946, 23 item(s)
    - January 19, 1946, 13 item(s)
    - January 21, 1946, 25 item(s)
    - January 22, 1946, 22 item(s)
    - January 23, 1946, 22 item(s)
    - January 24, 1946, 23 item(s)
    - January 25, 1946, 20 item(s)
    - January 28, 1946, 22 item(s)
    - January 29, 1946, 23 item(s)
    - January 30, 1946, 18 item(s)
    - January 31, 1946, 22 item(s)
  - February 1946, 433 item(s)
    - February 1, 1946, 21 item(s)
    - February 2, 1946, 11 item(s)
    - February 4, 1946, 21 item(s)
    - February 5, 1946, 22 item(s)
    - February 6, 1946, 11 item(s)
    - February 7, 1946, 24 item(s)
    - February 8, 1946, 19 item(s)
    - February 9, 1946, 6 item(s)
    - February 11, 1946, 21 item(s)
    - February 12, 1946, 21 item(s)
    - February 13, 1946, 21 item(s)
    - February 14, 1946, 20 item(s)
    - February 15, 1946, 20 item(s)
    - February 18, 1946, 19 item(s)
    - February 19, 1946, 20 item(s)
    - February 20, 1946, 17 item(s)
    - February 21, 1946, 23 item(s)
    - February 22, 1946, 21 item(s)
    - February 23, 1946, 15 item(s)
    - February 25, 1946, 19 item(s)
    - February 26, 1946, 20 item(s)
    - February 27, 1946, 21 item(s)
    - February 28, 1946, 20 item(s)
  - March 1946, 451 item(s)
    - March 1, 1946, 23 item(s)
    - March 2, 1946, 9 item(s)
    - March 4, 1946, 15 item(s)
    - March 5, 1946, 8 item(s)
    - March 6, 1946, 17 item(s)
    - March 7, 1946, 13 item(s)
    - March 8, 1946, 19 item(s)
    - March 11, 1946, 22 item(s)
    - March 12, 1946, 18 item(s)
    - March 13, 1946, 25 item(s)
    - March 14, 1946, 23 item(s)
    - March 15, 1946, 21 item(s)
    - March 16, 1946, 11 item(s)
    - March 18, 1946, 24 item(s)
    - March 19, 1946, 20 item(s)
    - March 20, 1946, 21 item(s)
    - March 21, 1946, 22 item(s)
    - March 22, 1946, 17 item(s)
    - March 23, 1946, 5 item(s)
    - March 25, 1946, 23 item(s)
    - March 26, 1946, 19 item(s)
    - March 27, 1946, 24 item(s)
    - March 28, 1946, 17 item(s)
    - March 29, 1946, 21 item(s)
    - March 30, 1946, 14 item(s)
  - April 1946, 479 item(s)
    - April 1, 1946, 25 item(s)
    - April 2, 1946, 22 item(s)
    - April 3, 1946, 19 item(s)
    - April 4, 1946, 21 item(s)
    - April 5, 1946, 21 item(s)
    - April 6, 1946, 11 item(s)
    - April 8, 1946, 23 item(s)
    - April 9, 1946, 23 item(s)
    - April 10, 1946, 26 item(s)
    - April 11, 1946, 26 item(s)
    - April 12, 1946, 23 item(s)
    - April 13, 1946, 10 item(s)
    - April 15, 1946, 23 item(s)
    - April 16, 1946, 24 item(s)
    - April 17, 1946, 24 item(s)
    - April 18, 1946, 19 item(s)
    - April 23, 1946, 24 item(s)
    - April 24, 1946, 21 item(s)
    - April 25, 1946, 24 item(s)
    - April 26, 1946, 22 item(s)
    - April 29, 1946, 23 item(s)
    - April 30, 1946, 25 item(s)
  - May 1946, 522 item(s)
    - May 1, 1946, 25 item(s)
    - May 2, 1946, 20 item(s)
    - May 3, 1946, 22 item(s)
    - May 4, 1946, 7 item(s)
    - May 6, 1946, 21 item(s)
    - May 7, 1946, 22 item(s)
    - May 8, 1946, 15 item(s)
    - May 9, 1946, 23 item(s)
    - May 10, 1946, 24 item(s)
    - May 11, 1946, 11 item(s)
    - May 13, 1946, 21 item(s)
    - May 14, 1946, 22 item(s)
    - May 15, 1946, 19 item(s)
    - May 16, 1946, 23 item(s)
    - May 17, 1946, 16 item(s)
    - May 18, 1946, 13 item(s)
    - May 20, 1946, 22 item(s)
    - May 21, 1946, 22 item(s)
    - May 22, 1946, 24 item(s)
    - May 23, 1946, 22 item(s)
    - May 24, 1946, 22 item(s)
    - May 27, 1946, 23 item(s)
    - May 28, 1946, 21 item(s)
    - May 29, 1946, 19 item(s)
    - May 30, 1946, 20 item(s)
    - May 31, 1946, 23 item(s)
  - June 1946, 465 item(s)
    - June 1, 1946, 11 item(s)
    - June 3, 1946, 19 item(s)
    - June 4, 1946, 21 item(s)
    - June 5, 1946, 23 item(s)
    - June 6, 1946, 22 item(s)
    - June 7, 1946, 20 item(s)
    - June 8, 1946, 10 item(s)
    - June 10, 1946, 22 item(s)
    - June 11, 1946, 21 item(s)
    - June 12, 1946, 21 item(s)
    - June 13, 1946, 20 item(s)
    - June 14, 1946, 21 item(s)
    - June 17, 1946, 21 item(s)
    - June 18, 1946, 22 item(s)
    - June 19, 1946, 21 item(s)
    - June 20, 1946, 23 item(s)
    - June 21, 1946, 24 item(s)
    - June 22, 1946, 11 item(s)
    - June 24, 1946, 22 item(s)
    - June 25, 1946, 22 item(s)
    - June 26, 1946, 21 item(s)
    - June 27, 1946, 12 item(s)
    - June 28, 1946, 24 item(s)
    - June 29, 1946, 11 item(s)
  - July 1946, 488 item(s)
    - July 1, 1946, 22 item(s)
    - July 2, 1946, 23 item(s)
    - July 3, 1946, 23 item(s)
    - July 4, 1946, 18 item(s)
    - July 5, 1946, 19 item(s)
    - July 8, 1946, 24 item(s)
    - July 9, 1946, 24 item(s)
    - July 10, 1946, 12 item(s)
    - July 11, 1946, 19 item(s)
    - July 12, 1946, 18 item(s)
    - July 15, 1946, 24 item(s)
    - July 16, 1946, 23 item(s)
    - July 17, 1946, 12 item(s)
    - July 18, 1946, 21 item(s)
    - July 19, 1946, 25 item(s)
    - July 22, 1946, 22 item(s)
    - July 23, 1946, 23 item(s)
    - July 24, 1946, 19 item(s)
    - July 25, 1946, 17 item(s)
    - July 26, 1946, 22 item(s)
    - July 27, 1946, 13 item(s)
    - July 29, 1946, 22 item(s)
    - July 30, 1946, 22 item(s)
    - July 31, 1946, 21 item(s)
  - August 1946, 460 item(s)
    - August 1, 1946, 21 item(s)
    - August 2, 1946, 23 item(s)
    - August 3, 1946, 11 item(s)
    - August 5, 1946, 20 item(s)
    - August 6, 1946, 22 item(s)
    - August 7, 1946, 21 item(s)
    - August 8, 1946, 10 item(s)
    - August 9, 1946, 23 item(s)
    - August 10, 1946, 11 item(s)
    - August 12, 1946, 22 item(s)
    - August 13, 1946, 20 item(s)
    - August 14, 1946, 11 item(s)
    - August 15, 1946, 11 item(s)
    - August 16, 1946, 21 item(s)
    - August 19, 1946, 8 item(s)
    - August 20, 1946, 22 item(s)
    - August 21, 1946, 21 item(s)
    - August 22, 1946, 18 item(s)
    - August 23, 1946, 19 item(s)
    - August 26, 1946, 23 item(s)
    - August 27, 1946, 22 item(s)
    - August 28, 1946, 21 item(s)
    - August 29, 1946, 21 item(s)
    - August 30, 1946, 20 item(s)
    - August 31, 1946, 18 item(s)
  - September 1946, 29 item(s)
  - October 1946, 18 item(s)
- Document books, 392 item(s)
  Compendia of exhibits presented at trial, compiled for judicial review, organized according to defendant.
  - Folders, 392 item(s)
- Empty folder, 148 item(s)
  These are digitized images of file folders that were archived originally as a part of the collection, but where the original contents may have been removed or relocated elsewhere before the digitization.
  - Folders, 148 item(s)
- Exhibits, 3462 item(s)
  These records contain documentary and physical evidence that was submitted at trial by the parties to the proceedings as exhibits for judicial review.
  - Affidavits, 135 item(s)
    - Envelopes, 6 item(s)
    - Folders, 129 item(s)
  - Defense exhibits, 943 item(s)
    - Folders, 931 item(s)
      - Defense Exhibit RAEDER No. 118, H-2029; 1 item(s) 6 pages Folders
        Arrangement
        PRELIMINARY NOTES TO EXHIBITS: In instances where an exhibit is loose in a folder, the pages of such exhibit have been counted manually
    - Microfilm, 12 item(s)
  - Great Britain exhibits, 617 item(s)
    - Folders, 613 item(s)
      - GB Exhibit 509, H-4030; 1 item(s) 18 pages Folders
    - Loose leaf folders, 4 item(s)
  - Republic of France exhibits, 742 item(s)
    - Books, 10 item(s)
    - Envelopes, 8 item(s)
    - Film, 1 item(s)
      - RF Exhibit 1152, H-4153; 1 item(s) 00:00:39 Film (Box 22)
        PRELIMINARY NOTES TO FILMS: Descriptions on film cans are not consistent; for example, exhibit numbers and/or film title are not always clearly stated. Therefore the film cans were thoroughly scrutinized as well as the films themselves. The descriptions which are lacking on the film cans are indicated below in parentheses.
        Occult Forces (or "Hidden Forces")
    - Folders, 720 item(s)
      - RF Exhibit 1119, H-4756; 1 item(s) 9 pages Folders
    - Package photostats, 1 item(s)
    - Photo albums, 1 item(s)
    - Volumes of bound newspapers, 1 item(s)
  - US exhibits, 958 item(s)
    - Film in box, 3 item(s)
      - USA Exhibit 167 "Nazi Plan" Reels 19-20, H-5243; 1 item(s) 00:17:21 Film in box (Box 27)
        Nazi Plan
      - USA Exhibit 167 "Nazi Plan" Reels 21-22, H-5244; 1 item(s) 00:15:13 Film in box (Box 27)
      - USA Exhibit 167 "Nazi Plan" Reel 1, H-5247; 1 item(s) 00:11:03 Film in box (Box 28)
        PRELIMINARY NOTES TO FILMS: Descriptions on film containers are not consistent; for example, exhibit number and/or film title are not always clearly stated. Therefore the film containers were thoroughly scrutinized as well as the films themselves. The descriptions which are lacking on the film containers are indicted below in parentheses.
    - Film in can, 18 item(s)
      - USA Exhibit 79: "Concentration Camps", Reel 1, H-4154; 1 item(s) 00:07:40 Film in can (Box 22)
        Concentration Camps
      - USA Exhibit 79: "Concentration Camps", Reel 2, H-4155; 1 item(s) 00:09:59 Film in can (Box 22)
      - USA Exhibit 79: "Concentration Camps", Reel 3, H-4156; 1 item(s) 00:06:25 Film in can (Box 22)
      - USA Exhibit 79: "Concentration Camps", Reel 4, H-4157; 1 item(s) 00:10:39 Film in can (Box 22)
      - USA Exhibit 79: "Concentration Camps", Reel 5, H-4158; 1 item(s) 00:11:36 Film in can (Box 22)
      - USA Exhibit 79: "Concentration Camps", Reel 6, H-4159; 1 item(s) 00:10:03 Film in can (Box 22)
      - USA Exhibit 167 "Nazi Plan" Reel 2, H-5248; 1 item(s) 00:07:29 Film in can (Box 28)
      - USA Exhibit 167 "Nazi Plan" Reel 3, H-5249; 1 item(s) 00:09:29 Film in can (Box 28)
      - USA Exhibit 167 "Nazi Plan" Reel 4, H-5250; 1 item(s) 00:06:37 Film in can (Box 28)
      - USA Exhibit 167 "Nazi Plan" Reel 5, H-5251; 1 item(s) 00:09:10 Film in can (Box 28)
      - USA Exhibit 167 "Nazi Plan" Reel 6, H-5252; 1 item(s) 00:10:20 Film in can (Box 28)
      - USA Exhibit 167 "Nazi Plan" Reel 7, H-5253; 1 item(s) 00:11:00 Film in can (Box 28)
      - USA Exhibit 167 "Nazi Plan" Reel 8, H-5254; 1 item(s) 00:05:53 Film in can (Box 28)
      - USA Exhibit 167 "Nazi Plan" Reel 9-10, H-5255; 1 item(s) 00:13:06 Film in can (Box 28)
      - USA Exhibit 167 "Nazi Plan" Reel 11-12, H-5256; 1 item(s) 00:20:36 Film in can (Box 28)
      - USA Exhibit 167 "Nazi Plan" Reel 13-14, H-5257; 1 item(s) 00:17:10 Film in can (Box 28)
      - USA Exhibit 167 "Nazi Plan" Reel 15-16, H-5258; 1 item(s) 00:18:02 Film in can (Box 28)
      - USA Exhibit 167 "Nazi Plan" Reel 17-18, H-5259; 1 item(s) 00:13:09 Film in can (Box 28)
    - Folders, 881 item(s)
      - USA Exhibit 532, H-3117; 1 item(s) 10 pages Folders
    - Loose leaf folders, 2 item(s)
    - Package photostats, 54 item(s)
  - USSR exhibits, 67 item(s)
    - Books, 6 item(s)
    - Envelopes, 35 item(s)
    - Film, 1 item(s)
      - USSR Exhibit 433, H-4175; 1 item(s) 00:23:50 Film (Box 22)
        Atrocities in Jugoslavia
    - Film in can, 14 item(s)
      - USSR Exhibit 81: "Atrocities", Reel 1, H-4160; 1 item(s) 00:09:40 Film in can (Box 22)
        Atrocities
      - USSR Exhibit 81: "Atrocities", Reel 2, H-4161; 1 item(s) 00:07:48 Film in can (Box 22)
      - USSR Exhibit 81: "Atrocities", Reel 3, H-4162; 1 item(s) 00:06:35 Film in can (Box 22)
      - USSR Exhibit 81: "Atrocities", Reel 4, H-4163; 1 item(s) 00:07:57 Film in can (Box 22)
      - USSR Exhibit 81: "Atrocities", Reel 5, H-4164; 1 item(s) 00:09:53 Film in can (Box 22)
      - USSR Exhibit 81: "Atrocities", Reel 6, H-4165; 1 item(s) 00:06:34 Film in can (Box 22)
      - USSR Exhibit 81: "Atrocities", Reel 7, H-4166; 1 item(s) 00:08:24 Film in can (Box 22)
      - USSR Exhibit 98: "Destruction of Culture", Reel 1, H-4167; 1 item(s) 00:12:20 Film in can (Box 22)
        Destruction of Culture
      - USSR Exhibit 98: "Destruction of Culture", Reel 2, H-4168; 1 item(s) 00:06:36 Film in can (Box 22)
      - USSR Exhibit 98: "Destruction of Culture", Reel 3, H-4169; 1 item(s) 00:05:50 Film in can (Box 22)
      - USSR Exhibit 401: "German Destruction in USSR", Reel 1, H-4171; 1 item(s) 00:10:29 Film in can (Box 22)
        German Destruction in USSR
      - USSR Exhibit 401: "German Destruction in USSR", Reel 2, H-4172; 1 item(s) 00:06:37 Film in can (Box 22)
      - USSR Exhibit 401: "German Destruction in USSR", Reel 3, H-4173; 1 item(s) 00:07:51 Film in can (Box 22)
      - USSR Exhibit 401: "German Destruction in USSR", Reel 4, H-4174; 1 item(s) 00:07:33 Film in can (Box 22)
    - Folders, 4 item(s)
    - Loose leaf folders, 5 item(s)
    - Loose leaf photo albums, 2 item(s)
- Final pleas and clemency pleas, 111 item(s)
  These records contain legal pleadings and supporting documentation from defense counsel for the accused, seeking review of judgments and clemency in sentencing.
  - Folders, 111 item(s)
- Indictments, 1 item(s)
  Official charging documents, authored by the prosecution, to indict those accused of crimes under the IMT Nuremberg Charter.
  - Envelopes, 1 item(s)
- Judgments, dissenting opinions, and sentences, 11 item(s)
  These records contain the final verdicts of the judges at the IMT Nuremberg, including dissenting opinions and sentences rendered against those found guilty of crimes charged.
  - Folders, 11 item(s)
- Lists, indices, and miscellaneous, 67 item(s)
  These materials include compilations and summaries of trial testimony and other evidence presented pertaining to the charges in the trial and the verdicts rendered against the accused.
  - Envelopes, 2 item(s)
  - Folders, 62 item(s)
  - Packages, 2 item(s)
  - Volumes, 1 item(s)
- Minutes of tribunal meetings, 1 item(s)
  Compendium of minutes recorded contemporaneously of meetings (9 Oct 1945 - 1 Oct 1946) where the judges of the IMT Nuremberg convened to discuss and decide administrative and procedural matters.
  - Folders, 1 item(s)
- Official commission transcripts, 234 item(s)
  These are the official transcripts of the Commissions appointed by the IMT for the hearing of witnesses or the presentation of affidavits relating to the accused organizations. Recorded contemporaneously by professional clerks.
  - Folders, 234 item(s)
- Official court transcripts, 723 item(s)
  These records are contemporaneous transcription of live courtroom proceedings at the IMT Nuremberg, recorded by professional clerks of the tribunal and archived with the records of trial.
  - November 1945, 28 item(s)
  - December 1945, 45 item(s)
  - January 1946, 90 item(s)
  - February 1946, 80 item(s)
  - March 1946, 75 item(s)
  - April 1946, 66 item(s)
  - May 1946, 78 item(s)
  - June 1946, 72 item(s)
  - July 1946, 71 item(s)
  - August 1946, 75 item(s)
  - September 1946, 3 item(s)
    - Folders, 2 item(s)
    - Volumes, 1 item(s)
  - October 1946, 1 item(s)
  - Envelopes, 1 item(s)
  - Volumes, 38 item(s)
- Rules, rulings, and orders, 10 item(s)
  Rules of procedure and evidence promulgated by the IMT Nuremberg to govern the proceedings of trial.
  - Envelopes, 3 item(s)
  - Folders, 7 item(s)
- Statements and speeches, 56 item(s)
  These are the text of the opening and closing statements delivered by prosecuting attorneys at the trial.